the universe delivers to me
every lesson i need to learn to become
who i'm supposed to be
generally they're little tiny lessons
that happen throughout the day when i
encounter emotions about other people
when i see messages in nature or just
the perfect thing is
is given to me by like the facebook
algorithm from the youtube algorithm
but sometimes those events are more
profound and bigger
and this is one of them that happened
two years ago and i'm reminded of it
because i keep this daily journal for my
kid and when i was writing in it
yesterday i looked back
and two years ago tomorrow which is
today
um i they've written it
in the voice of my child is like the
neighbor came over and made mom cry
and then it is this friend on facebook's
birthday
and the reason we're friends is because
two years ago for their 28th birthday
and the 28
28 is a number that means something to
me they put out a call for free coaching
and i took them up on that opportunity
and then i ended up paying for
some coaching sessions with them after
after that not just the free one which
is unique for me
i generally don't it's too much money
too too expensive to pay for those
things but this was worth it there was
something to do i was like
yes i need to pay for this i need to
work with this person
so then this day came around i was
house-sitting
dog sitting for friends of mine in the
community we're part of
we know everyone there all of the
neighbors we've been
instrumental in creating it and helping
bring it forth we've been involved since
the beginning
and um like my daughter was born into
this community even though we don't
physically live there
even though they moved in two and a half
three years after she was she was born
but we had to like get it through the
city and do all that so
we eat there three or it's uh two to
three times a week before coping
these were like our our people and
one of the neighbors comes over
the neighbor's kid was over playing with
my kid and then one of the older
neighbors
from downstairs comes upstairs comes
inside and he's like
you guys walked me up for my nap i was
like oh girls you opened you woke so and
so up from her nap
and she proceeds to say something that i
was like what i couldn't
have just heard the just like i'm gonna
make sure you leave and never come back
and she leaves and i was like i could
not have heard what i just heard
so i go downstairs to her door to find
out that she need us to still leave is
she still having a nap
and she starts yelling at me that she
hates me she's always hated me
i'm a freeloader i was like listen like
i understand needing a nap i also need
one every day
i have a disability no you don't have a
disability you're a freeloader
you and your daughter need to leave and
never come back and she's just like
same things over and over again just
like over the top
mean saying the things in my head that
aren't saying the things out loud that
are in my head that i'm scared people
think about me
and it is not an event i would have
chosen
it was my adrenaline was high i was
crying for like days afterwards that
this thing happened
but it was exactly what was supposed to
happen because the things that unfolded
after that
over the course of the next year and
years as well as
like write directly around that so i
went from like what did i do to this
poor sweet woman to finding out she does
this
all the time she's like saccharine sweet
until she's not flies off the handle and
says like
the meanest things that she um can
just like finds it she she asks you
questions about your life so she can use
these things in her older invulnerable
moments i don't know
but like both the learning that someone
could be involved in an intentional
community
be in their 70s and she's been involved
for decades in intentional community
and be like you know a fairly wealthy
homeowner
okay she's doing all right for herself
and just
not be an okay human being like just
okay this is but delivery messages
delivery lessons to the rest of the
world so
i ended up becoming closer to the
community over this because i realized i
had this fear of being
removed over a conflict right if i had
conflict with anyone
i don't live there so i'm the one who's
gonna be removed but
i wasn't like i didn't do anything wrong
in that situation uh
having someone say the things are in my
head and worrying that everyone else
also felt them and be like no we don't
feel that way
we know what a lot of them also have
disabilities they also know what it's
like
and that she had
called me a freeloader and there was a
part of that that hurt because i'm not
able to show up in the same way and i'm
not able to
attend the big cleaning events that
happen twice a year because they're
they're
too long too big too loud to everything
so because i felt bad about it i was
like okay what can i do and so i started
cleaning the yoga room every two weeks
because it was something within my
capacity to do i could do it was a tiny
thing
every two weeks instead of a big thing
twice a year it was it's quiet up there
i can put on music
and just and just zen out and i could do
it on like a thursday if i couldn't do
it on wednesday it just worked for me
but what happened after that event both
all that learning and community and like
that also the community is not set up
for conflict resolution
it's not set up for like holding this
woman in any way accountable
but it's not on me because i was i was
like i went from like what did i do to
this woman to like
wait why do we let her get away with
this why is this okay why are you all
no cool interesting interesting
um working with this feelings coach
i had this ev this event so that
paralleled her freaking out on me
i was the next night or the night after
where she had been leaving to europe
she's now gone and off to europe
and i was then leaving from dog sitting
to come back here the next day so there
was this
board game event in the common house i
really wanted to go to once my kid was
asleep and she like would not go to
sleep
would not lay down would not do anything
and so i
oh i have this feeling of anger that
i've never had before like it was like i
wanted to commit acts of violence and it
scared me
and so i ended i did not go to games
tonight i ended up putting out a call to
both my feelings coach like what is this
that's coming up i need help oh my god
are you gonna are you gonna not work
with me because these are scary emotions
that i have right now
and i put out a call to this facebook
group that i'm part of i've been part of
since my daughter was born about the
same thing like the same story
i'm scared as anyone else felt this
towards their kid before is anyone else
felt this much intense anger what did
you do
and neither of them responded and i was
like everybody hates me
i'm the worst human being ever with my
anger
and um and but but i'm like i need to
get this oh and i can't go for a walk my
kid's asleep and i was like oh
i'm at co housing though like i can go
for a walk up and down the courtyard
i can hear my kid if anything happens
she said anyway so i went out
the first person i encountered was this
other older woman who's part of the
community and i was like i don't know
do you know anything about anger
management like i'm having a moment
and she was like actually yeah that's
what i do it's like oh
interesting how perfect that abstaining
community right now when this happens
that it was brought out at this time and
she helped me with a few techniques
um and then when i got back there was
also i
had so many responses from the facebook
community and my coach had written back
which honestly was her birthday his
birthday i'm reminded now that it was
his birthday
and when he had put out the call for his
um
to give coaching for his birthday and it
was his 28th birthday
he's so he's 30 today and i'm oh just
like all of these things coming together
and what it unfolded
over so because i had felt that intense
anger i ended up getting
um introduced to teal swan and
as well as this book by i can't remember
his name at the
i want to say tibetan that's not right
vietnamese monk who has a book about
anger
and just not suppressing it anymore and
figuring out how to work with it and how
to not take it out on people hopefully
but but find ways to
channel it that i had like 30 plus years
of anger in my body that i hadn't been
able to express
and that doesn't mean i have 30 years to
now express it
but how do i let that out and
having this instant karma where i went
from being the person that the anger was
reflected at to be in the person
that reflected it having this
all of my bias because i was like why is
this woman not
a better human being like she's she's
older
she's been an intentional community
which is supposed to kind of help you
soften your rough edges she chooses to
be an intentional community she's been
intentional with me for decades
and she is a homeowner
and it was that piece where i was like
why does that mean she should be a
better human being like i was
like she's more well off she has more
money she has more connections and i was
like that
it doesn't mean anything actually it
helped me bring to surface my bias and
my worry about like
being connected to this community and
what people thought about me and it also
showed
that these negative events can still be
positive
and if that hadn't happened six months
later when my sister
said some mean hurtful things to me
about my disability i would have been in
a much worse space because
the things that were in my head someone
had said them to me and i survived and i
was like that's not on me that's on you
and uh yeah i was able to walk away from
my sister for a year and a half when she
said
some of the same things six months later
so
i just wanted to share that because it's
what i just
i didn't know was on his birthday and i
didn't know
i'm so grateful that i keep this this
journal so i so i knew
i knew that it was the anniversary of
that and what has unfolded since then
and i wanted to share that with you and
if you want the
i'm going to link to the the next story
with the neighbor
it happened this year when we when we
stayed there
anyway i'll see you next time